Igor Simões Personal Website isol2@cin.ufpe.br +55 81 9-9859-2804

Address

Rua Frei Jaboatão, 35 Torre 50710-030 Recife, Pernambuco Brazil

Igor Simões de Oliveira Lima

Test Engineer

About Me

Bachelor in Computer Science by Federal University of Alagoas - Campus Arapiraca. I was a research fellow at Laboratory of Analysis, Modeling and Programming (LAMP) at Federal University of Alagoas. In 2016, I was resident in the Sequential Course of Complementary Training in Test Analysis by the Motorola Mobility at CIn-UFPE where I worked as a QA Test Analyst and Developer in the Automation Team, performing the automation of testing cases in mobile applications.

Education

Jan 2016 - Dec 2016, Federal University of Pernambuco - CIn

Sequential Course of Complementary Training in Software Engineering with emphasis on Software Testing by Motorola Mobility and CIn-UFPE.

Feb 2011 - Jan 2017, Federal University of Alagoas

BS in Computer Science.

Experience

Jan 2016 - Dec 2016, *QA Test Analyst*, Project Motorola Mobility/CIn-UFPE

Knowledge adquired:

- Software testing for Motorola mobile phones:
 - GSM / 2G
 - UMTS / 3G
 - HPSA / 3.5G
 - LTE / 4G
- Analysis and Reporting in JIRA tools
- Execution of test cases:
 - Manual
 - Semi-automatic
 - Automatic
- Types of tests:
 - Black-box testing / Functional
 - Sanity
 - Regression
- Automation with UIAutomator

Jan 2013 - Dec 2015, *Software Developer*, Laboratory of Analysis, Modeling and Programming (LAMP) - UFAL

Developing applications for Academic Researches using Java and JavaFX. One of them was a desktop application to support the learning of physics on a digital board using JBox2D to create a environment with gravity, velocity and others metrics. I worked also in another project implementing a plugin for monitoring students actions in Geany IDE(Integrated Development Environment) to display the metrics collected in a Django server.

Igor Simões Personal Website isol2@cin.ufpe.br +55 81 9-9859-2804

Address

Rua Frei Jaboatão, 35 Torre 50710-030 Recife, Pernambuco Brazil

Software Development Skills

Programming

- Python
 - Django
 - Flask
- Javascript
 - NodeJS
 - ReactJS
 - React-Native
 - MeteorJS
 - AngularJS
 - Ionic

- Ruby
 - Ruby on Rails

Computer Software

- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB

- Android
- Hybrid Apps
- Git

Java

- JIRA
- Jenkins

Interests

Professional

Programming, Software Engineering, Web Apps, Mobile Apps, Hybrid Apps, Data Analysis.

Personal

Guitar, Acoustic Guitar, Ukulele, Games, Cooking and Craft Beer.